<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="monitoring-tickets" >
<title>チケット責任者とチケットの監視</title>

<para>
OTRS
2.1からチケットの所有者に加えて、１チケットに対して１名の責任者を割り当てることが可能です。さらに、チケットと関係のある全ての活動はチケットの所有者以外の誰かに見られるようにできます。これらの2つの機能性は、チケット責任者（TicketResponsible）とチケット監視者（TicketWatcher）としてインプリメントされ、タスクの割り当ておよび階層的チーム構造内に働くことを手助けします。
</para>

<section id="ticket-responsible" >
<title>チケット責任者</title>

<para>
The ticket responsibility feature facilitates the complete processing of a
ticket by an agent other than the ticket owner. Thus an agent who has locked
a ticket can pass it on to another agent, who is not the ticket owner, in
order for the second to respond to a customer request. After the request has
been dealt with, the first agent can withdraw the ticket responsibility from
the second agent.
</para>

<para>
With the configuration parameter <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Ticket:Core::Ticket:Ticket::Responsible">Ticket::Responsible</link>,
the ticket responsibility feature can be activated. This will cause 3 new
links to appear in the ticket activities menu of a zoomed ticket in the
agent interface.
</para>

<para>
チケット責任者は、チケット内容を呼び出して割り当てることができます。そしてチケット活動メニュー「責任者」リンク（担当者インターフェイスにあるズームチケットにある）をクリックします。（下図参照）
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Changing the Responsibility of a ticket in its zoomed view</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/ticket/ticket-zoom-responsible.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
After clicking on "Responsible", a pop-up dialog to change the
responsibility of that ticket will open (see figure below). This dialog can
also be used to send a message to the new responsible agent.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Pop-up dialog to change a ticket's responsibility</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/ticket/ticket-responsible.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
チケット責任者機能が活性化されるとすぐに、担当者が責任を負う全チケットのリストは、OTRS担当者インターフェイスの責任者ビューを通してアクセスできます。
</para>

</section>

<section id="ticket-watcher">
<title>チケットの監視</title>

<para>
OTRS2.1から　「チケット監視」機能を使えば　スーパバイザのような担当者を選ぶことにより、システム内の特定のチケットを処理することなく監視することができます。
</para>

<para>
The TicketWatcher feature can be activated with the configuration parameter
<link
linkend="ConfigReference_Ticket:Core::TicketWatcher:Ticket::Watcher">Ticket::Watcher</link>
which adds new links to your actions toolbar. Using <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Ticket:Core::TicketWatcher:Ticket::WatcherGroup">Ticket::WatcherGroup</link>,
one or more user groups with permission to watch tickets can also be
defined.
</para>

<para>
In order to watch a ticket, go to its zoomed view and click on the
"Subscribe" link in the ticket activities menu (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Subscribing to watching a ticket in its zoomed view</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/ticket/ticket-subscribe.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
If you no longer want to watch a specific ticket, go to its zoomed view and
click on the "Unsubscribe" link in the ticket activities menu (see figure
below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Unsubscribing from watching a ticket in its zoomed view</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/ticket/ticket-unsubscribe.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
The list of all watched tickets can be accessed through the Watched view of
the OTRS agent interface (see figure below), as soon as the ticket watcher
feature gets activated.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Watched tickets view</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/ticket/ticket-subscribe-mailbox.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>
</section>

</section>
