<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="email">
<title>Sending/Receiving Emails</title>

<section id="email-sending">
<title>Sending Emails</title>

<section id="email-sending-sendmail">
<title>Via Sendmail (Default)</title>

<para>
OTRS can send out emails via <ulink
url="http://www.sendmail.org/">Sendmail</ulink>, <ulink
url="http://www.postfix.org/">Postfix</ulink>, <ulink
url="http://www.qmail.org">Qmail</ulink> or <ulink
url="http://www.exim.org">Exim</ulink>. The default configuration is to use
Sendmail and should work out-of-the-box.
</para>

<para>
Die Konfiguration kann über die <link
linkend="adminarea-sysconfig">grafische Administrationsoberfläche</link>
(Framework::Core::Sendmail) vorgenommen werden
</para>

</section>

<section id="email-sending-smtp">
<title>Via SMTP Server or Smarthost</title>

<para>
OTRS kann E-Mails via SMTP  (<ulink
url="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc821.txt">Simple Mail Transfer Protocol / RFC
821</ulink>) oder Secure SMTP versenden.
</para>

<para>
Die SMTP-Einstellungen können über die SysConfig vorgenommen werden
(Framework::Core::Sendmail). Wenn SMTPS nicht als Option auftaucht, fehlen
benötigte Perl-Module. Lesen Sie in diesem Fall im Abschnitt <link
linkend="installation-of-perl-modules"> "Installation benötigter
Perl-Module" </link> nach.
</para>

</section>

</section>

<section id="email-receiving">
<title>Receiving Emails</title>

<section id="email-receiving-pop3">
<title>Mail Accounts Configured via the OTRS GUI</title>

<para>
OTRS is able to receive emails from POP3, POP3S, IMAP and IMAPS mail
accounts.
</para>

<para>
Configure your mail accounts via the "PostMaster Mail Accounts" link on the
Admin page.
</para>

<para>
If a new mail account is to be created (see figure below), then its mail
server name, login name and password must be specified. Also, you need to
select the mail server type, which can be POP3, POP3S, IMAP or IMAPS. If you
don't see your server type available as an option, the required Perl modules
are missing on your system. In that case, please refer to <link
linkend="installation-of-perl-modules"> "Installation of Perl modules
required for OTRS"</link> for instructions.</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Einen E-Mail-Account hinzufügen</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/email/add-mailaccount.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>Wählen Sie für "Vertraut" den Wert "Ja" aus, dann werden die
sog. X-OTRS-Header-Einträge ausgewertet und angewendet, sofern derartige
Header-Einträge in einer abgerufenen Nachricht vorhanden sind. Da mit Hilfe
der X-OTRS-Header einige Dinge am System beeinflusst werden können, sollten
Sie "Vertraut" nur auf "Ja" setzen, wenn Sie genau wissen, von welchen
Absendern die abgerufenen Nachrichten stammen. X-OTRS-Header werden vom
<link linkend="adminarea-postmasterfilter">Modul für die
Nachrichtenfilterung</link> in OTRS benutzt, die X-OTRS-Header werden <link
linkend="table-of-x-otrs-headers">in dieser Tabelle</link> näher
beschrieben.Eventuell eingerichtete Filterregeln werden auf jeden Fall
abgearbietet, egal welcher Wert für "Vertraut" ausgewählt wurde.
</para>

<para>
The distribution of incoming messages can be controlled if they need to be
sorted by queue or by the content of the "To:" field. For the Dispatching
field, if "Dispatching by selected queue" is selected, all incoming messages
will be sorted into the specified queue. The address where the mail was sent
to is disregarded in this case. If "Dispatching by email To: field" is
selected, the system checks if a queue is linked with the address in the To:
field of the incoming mail. You can link an address to a queue in the <link
linkend="adminarea-emailaddresses">E-mail address management</link> section
of the Admin page. If the address in the To: field is linked with a queue,
the new message will be sorted into the linked queue. If no link is found
between the address in the To: field and any queue, then the message flows
into the "Raw" queue in the system, which is the <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Ticket:Core::PostMaster:PostmasterDefaultQueue">PostmasterDefaultQueue</link>
after a default installation.
</para>

<para>
All data for the mail accounts are saved in the OTRS database. The
<filename>bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::PostMaster::MailAccountFetch</filename>
command uses the settings in the database and fetches the mail. You can
execute it manually to check if all your mail settings are working properly.
</para>

<para>
On a normal installation, the mail will be fetched every 10 minutes by the
OTRS Daemon.
</para>

<note>
<para>
Beim Abholen löscht OTRS die E-Mails vom POP oder IMAP server. Es besteht
keine Möglichkeit, die Mails dort zu erhalten. Wenn Sie dies wünschen,
erstellen Sie am Besten Weiterleitungsregeln auf Ihrem Mail-Server. Lesen
Sie hierzu bitte in der Dokumentation ihres Mail-Servers nach.
</para>
</note>
</section>


<section id="email-receiving-cmd">
<title>Via Command Line Program and Procmail (<literal>otrs.Console.pl
Maint::PostMaster::Read</literal>)</title>

<para>
If you cannot use mail accounts to get the email into OTRS, the command line
program <filename>bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::PostMaster::Read</filename>
might be a way around the problem. It takes the mails via STDIN and pipes
them directly into OTRS. That means email will be available in your OTRS
system if the MDA (mail delivery agent, e.g. procmail) executes this
program.
</para>

<para>
To test <filename>bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::PostMaster::Read</filename>
without an MDA, execute the command of the following script.
</para>

<para>
<screen>
linux:/opt/otrs# cd bin
linux:/opt/otrs/bin# cat ../doc/sample_mails/test-email-1.box | ./otrs.Console.pl Maint::PostMaster::Read
linux:/opt/otrs/bin#
</screen>
</para>

<para>
<emphasis>Skript: PostMaster-Test ohne MDA.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
Wird die E-Mail in der Queue-Ansicht angezeigt, sind Ihre Einstellungen in
Ordnung.
</para>

<example id='procmail-queue-routing'>

<title>Routing via Procmail Using <literal>otrs.Console.pl</literal></title>

<para>
In order to route mails in a specific queue using otrs.Console.pl use the
following example.
</para>

<para>
<screen><![CDATA[
| $SYS_HOME/bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::PostMaster::Read --target-queue=QUEUENAME
]]></screen>
</para>

<para>
When sorting to a subqueue, you must seperate the parent and child queue
"::".
</para>

<para>
<screen><![CDATA[
| $SYS_HOME/bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::PostMaster::Read --target-queue=QUEUENAME::SUBQUEUE
]]></screen>
</para>

</example>

<para>
Procmail ist in der Linux-Umgebung ein sehr bekannter E-Mail-Filter, der
höchstwahrscheinlich auf Ihrem System installiert sein wird. Falls nicht,
erhalten Sie auf der <ulink
url="http://www.procmail.org/"><citetitle>procmail
Homepage</citetitle></ulink> weitere Informationen.
</para>

<para>
Um procmail einzurichten (benötigt einen für procmail konfigurierten MDA
(z. B. sendmail, postfix, exim oder qmail)), kann die
Datei<filename>.procmailrc.dist</filename> aus dem OTRS-Homeverzeichnis
verwendet werden. Kopieren Sie <filename>.procmailrc.dist</filename> nach
<filename>.procmailrc</filename> und nehmen Sie die in Skript: dargestellten
Änderungen vor.
</para>

<para>
<programlisting>
SYS_HOME=$HOME
PATH=/bin:/usr/bin:/usr/local/bin
# --
# Pipe all email into the PostMaster process.
# --
:0 :
| $SYS_HOME/bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::PostMaster::Read
</programlisting>
</para>

<para>
<emphasis>Skript: Konfiguration von procmail für OTRS.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
All email sent to the local OTRS user will be piped into
<filename>bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::PostMaster::Read</filename> and then
shown in your QueueView.
</para>

</section>

<section id="email-receiving-fetchmail">
<title>Fetching emails via POP3 or IMAP and fetchmail for otrs.Console.pl
Maint::PostMaster::Read</title>

<para>
In order to get email from your mail server, via a POP3 or IMAP mailbox, to
the OTRS machine/local OTRS account and to procmail, use <ulink
url="http://www.fetchmail.info/">fetchmail</ulink>.
</para>

<note>
<para>
Voraussetzung ist eine funktionierende SMTP-Konfiguration auf dem
OTRS-Rechner.
</para>
</note>

<para>
You can use the <filename>.fetchmailrc.dist</filename> in the home directory
of OTRS and copy it to <filename>.fetchmailrc</filename>. Modfiy/change it
for your needs (see the Example below).
</para>

<example id='fetchmailrc'>
<title><literal>.fetchmailrc</literal></title>

<para>
<programlisting>
#poll (mailserver) protocol POP3 user (user) password (password) is (localuser)
poll mail.example.com protocol POP3 user joe password mama is otrs
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
Don't forget to set the <filename>.fetchmailrc</filename> to 710 ("chmod 710
.fetchmailrc")!
</para>

<para>
With the <filename>.fetchmailrc</filename> from the Example above, all email
will be forwarded to the local OTRS account, if the command
<command>fetchmail -a</command> is executed. Set up a cronjob with this
command if you want to fetch the mails regularly.
</para>
</section>


<section id="email-receiving-filter">
<title>Filtering/Dispatching by OTRS/PostMaster Modules (for More Complex
Dispatching)</title>

<para>
If you use the <filename>bin/otrs.Console.pl
Maint::PostMaster::Read</filename> or <filename>bin/otrs.Console.pl
Maint::PostMaster::MailAccountFetch</filename> method, you can insert or
modify X-OTRS header entries with the PostMaster filter modules. With the
X-OTRS headers, the ticket system can execute some actions on incoming
mails, sort them into a specific queue, change the priority or change the
customer ID, for example. More information about the X-OTRS headers are
available in the section about <link
linkend="adminarea-postmasterpop3-account">adding mail accounts</link> from
the OTRS Admin page.
</para>

<para>
Es gibt verschiedene Standard-Filtermodule:
</para>

<note>
<para>
Der Jobname
(z. B. $Self-&gt;{"PostMaster::PreFilterModule"}-&gt;{"Jobname"}) muss
eindeutig sein!
</para>
</note>

<para>
Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::Match is a default module to match on
some email header (e.g. From, To, Subject, ...). It can set new email
headers (e.g. X-OTRS-Ignore: yes or X-OTRS-Queue: spam) if a filter rule
matches. The jobs of the Example below can be inserted in
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>
</para>

<example id='filter-module-match-example'>
<title>Beispiel-Jobs für das Filtermodul Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::Match</title>

<para>
<programlisting>
    # Job Name: 1-Match
    # (block/ignore all spam email with From: noreply@)
    $Self-&gt;{'PostMaster::PreFilterModule'}-&gt;{'1-Match'} = {
        Module =&gt; 'Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::Match',
        Match =&gt; {
            From =&gt; 'noreply@',
        },
        Set =&gt; {
            'X-OTRS-Ignore' =&gt; 'yes',
        },
    };
    # Job Name: 2-Match
    # (sort emails with From: sales@example.com and Subject: **ORDER**
    # into queue 'Order')
    $Self-&gt;{'PostMaster::PreFilterModule'}-&gt;{'2-Match'} = {
        Module =&gt; 'Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::Match',
        Match =&gt; {
            To =&gt; 'sales@example.com',
            Subject =&gt; '**ORDER**',
        },
        Set =&gt; {
            'X-OTRS-Queue' =&gt; 'Order',
        },
    };
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::CMD is a default module to pipe the
email into an external command. The output is given to STDOUT and if the
result is true, then set new email header (e.g. X-OTRS-Ignore: yes or
X-OTRS-Queue: spam). The Example below can be used in
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>
</para>

<example id='filter-module-cmd-example'>
<title>Beispiel-Job für das Filtermodul Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::CMD</title>

<para>
<programlisting>
    # Job Name: 5-SpamAssassin
    # (SpamAssassin example setup, ignore spam emails)
    $Self-&gt;{'PostMaster::PreFilterModule'}-&gt;{'5-SpamAssassin'} = {
        Module =&gt; 'Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::CMD',
        CMD =&gt; '/usr/bin/spamassassin | grep -i "X-Spam-Status: yes"',
        Set =&gt; {
            'X-OTRS-Ignore' =&gt; 'yes',
        },
    };
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
    Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::ExternalTicketNumberRecognition is a
default module that adds the possibility to parse external identifiers, in
the email subject, the body or both using regular expressions. It then
stores this value in a defined dynamic field. When an email comes in, OTRS
will first search for an external identifier and when it finds one, query
OTRS on the pre-defined dynamic field. If it finds an existing ticket, it
will update this ticket, otherwise it will create a new ticket with the
external reference number in the separate field.
</para>
<para>
    OTRS SysConfig already provide 4 different settings to setup different
external ticket numbers.  If more settings are needed they need to be added
manually. The following example can be used in
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> to extend SysConfig settings.
</para>

<example id='filter-module-externalticketrecognition-example'>
    <title>
        Beispiel-Jobs für das Filtermodul
Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::ExternalTicketNumberRecognition
    </title>

<programlisting language="Perl"><![CDATA[
    # Job Name: ExternalTicketNumberRecognition
    # External Ticket Number Reconition, check for Incident-<number> in incoming mails subject and
    # body from the addeesses <sender>@externalticket.com, if number is found it will be stored in
    # the dynamic field 'ExternalNumber' (that need to be setup in the Admin Panel).
    $Self->{'PostMaster::PreFilterModule'}->{'000-ExternalTicketNumberRecognition'} = {
        'FromAddressRegExp' => '\\s*@externalticket.com',
        'NumberRegExp'      => 'Incident-(\\d.*)',
        'SearchInSubject'   => '1',
        'SearchInBody'      => '1',
        'TicketStateTypes'  => 'new;open'
        'DynamicFieldName'  => 'ExternalNumber',
        'Module'            => 'Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::ExternalTicketNumberRecognition',
        'Name'              => 'Test External Ticket Number',
        'SenderType'        => 'system',
    };
    ]]></programlisting></example>

<itemizedlist mark="round">
    <para><emphasis>Konfigurationsoptionen</emphasis></para>
    <listitem>
        <para>FromAddressRegExp</para>
        <para>
            This is an optional setting. Only mails matching this "From:" address will
be considered for this filter. You can adjust this setting to the sender
address your external system uses for outgoing mails. In case this address
can differ, you can set this option to empty. OTRS will in that case not
check the sender address.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>NumberRegExp</para>
        <para>
            This is a mandatory setting. This setting contains the regular expression
OTRS will use to extract the ticket number out of the subject and/or ticket
body. The default regular expression will match occurrences of for example
'Incident-12354' and will put the part between parentheses in the dynamic
field field, in this case '12354'.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>SearchInSubject</para>
        <para>Wenn diese Variable auf '1' gesetzt ist, wird der E-Mailbetreff nach einer
Ticketnummer durchsucht.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>SearchInBody</para>
        <para>Wenn diese Variable auf '1' gesetzt ist, wird der E-Mailbody nach einer
Ticketnummer durchsucht.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>TicketStateTypes</para>
        <para>
            This is an optional setting. If given, it will search OTRS only for open
external tickets of given state types. The state types are separated with
semicolons.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>DynamicField</para>
        <para>
            This is a required setting. It defines the dynamic filed that is used to
store the external number (the field name must exist in the system and has
to be valid).
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>SenderType</para>
        <para>Definiert den Absender Typ welcher bei der Ticket erstellung verwendet wird.</para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<para>
Natürlich ist es auch möglich, eigene PostMaster-Filtermodule zu entwickeln.
</para>

</section>

<section id="email-filter-troubleshooting">
    <title>Troubleshooting Email Filtering</title>
    <para>This section shows some common issues and things to consider when
troubleshooting Postmaster filters.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>The filters are worked in order of their alphabetically sorted filter
names.The last filter wins for a certain field to be set, when the criteria
matches twice.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>"Stop After Match" can prevent a second match.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Make sure the regular expression is valid.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Headers can be set as to control OTRS, but are not written in the mail
itself.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>When matching one From, CC, TO, use EMAILADDRESS: &lt;your@address&gt;</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The Mailbox must be trusted.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>The match criteria are AND conditions.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Ticket properties can not be matched by the postmaster filter.</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</section>

</section>

</section>
