<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-auto-responses">
<title>Majibu ya otomatiki</title>

<para>
OTRS allows you to send automatic responses to customers based on the
occurrence of certain events, such as the creation of a ticket in a specific
queue, the receipt of a follow-up message in regards to a ticket, the
closure or rejection of a ticket, etc. To manage such responses, click the
link "Auto responses" on the Admin page (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Auto response management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-autoresponse.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
To create an automatic response, click on the button "Add auto response",
provide the needed data and submit it (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Adding an auto response</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-autoresponse.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
Mada na nakala ya majibu otomatiki yanaweza kuzalishwa na vishika nafasi,
kama saini na salamu. Kama ukiingiza, kwa mfano, kishika nafasi
&lt;OTRS_CUSTOMER_EMAIL[5]&gt; kwenye kiini cha jibu otomatiki, mistari 5 ya
kwanza ya barua ya mteja itaingizwa kwenye jibu otomatiki. Utapata undani
zaidi kuhusu vishika nafasi halali ambavyo vinaweza kutumika upande wa chini
wa skrini iliyoonyeshwa kwenye Kielelezo.
</para>

<para>
For every automatic answer, you can specify the event that should trigger
it. The system events that are available after a default installation are
described in the Table 4-4.
</para>

<table id="table-of-autoanswer-types">
<title>Events for auto responses</title>
  <tgroup cols="2">
    <thead>
      <row>
        <entry>
          Jina
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Maelezo
        </entry>
      </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <row>
        <entry>
          jibu otomatiki
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Utengenezaji wa tiketi katika foleni fulani
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          jibu otomatiki/tiketi mpya
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Ufunguzi wa tiketi iliyofungwa, mf. mteja akijibu hiyo tiketi.
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          ufwatiliaji otomatiki
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Upokeaji wa ufwatiliaji wa tiketi.
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          kukataa kiotomatiki
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Ukataaji otomatiki wa tiketi, unafanywa na mfumo.
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          ondoa kiotomatiki
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Ufutaji wa tiketi, unafanywa na mfumo.
        </entry>
      </row>
    </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</table>

<note>
<para>
Kama ilivyo kwa vyombo vingine vya OTRS, majibu otomatiki pia haiwezi
kufutwa, inalemazwa tu kwa kuseti chaguo Halali kuwa
<emphasis>batili</emphasis> au <emphasis>batili-kwa muda</emphasis>.
</para>
</note>

<para>
To add an auto response to a queue, use the "Auto Response &lt;-&gt; Queues"
link on the Admin page (see figure below). All system events are listed for
every queue, and an auto answer with the same event can be selected or
removed via a listbox.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Queue &lt;-&gt; auto response relations management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-autoresponse-queue.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
To define the different auto responses that will be available for a queue,
click on the corresponding queue name (see figure below). It is also
possible to edit an existing auto response - to do so, click on the response
and edit in the same manner as editing a new auto response.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Change auto response relations for a queue</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/autoresponses-queues-relations.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

</section>
