<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-auto-responses">
<title>自動応答</title>

<para>
OTRS allows you to send automatic responses to customers based on the
occurrence of certain events, such as the creation of a ticket in a specific
queue, the receipt of a follow-up message in regards to a ticket, the
closure or rejection of a ticket, etc. To manage such responses, click the
link "Auto responses" on the Admin page (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Auto response management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-autoresponse.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
To create an automatic response, click on the button "Add auto response",
provide the needed data and submit it (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Adding an auto response</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-autoresponse.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
署名と挨拶文でそうであったように、自動応答の件名およびテキストは、変数によって生成することができます。例えば、自動応答の本文に可変&lt;OTRS_CUSTOMER_EMAIL[5]&gt;を挿入すれば、顧客メール・テキストの最初の5行が自動応答に挿入されるでしょう。図示された画面の一番下にて使用することができる有効な変数に関するより多くの詳細を見つけるでしょう。
</para>

<para>
For every automatic answer, you can specify the event that should trigger
it. The system events that are available after a default installation are
described in the Table 4-4.
</para>

<table id="table-of-autoanswer-types">
<title>Events for auto responses</title>
  <tgroup cols="2">
    <thead>
      <row>
        <entry>
          Name
        </entry>
        <entry>
          摘要
        </entry>
      </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <row>
        <entry>
          自動応答
        </entry>
        <entry>
          あるキュー中のチケットの自動返答生成
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          自動応答/新規チケット
        </entry>
        <entry>
          既に完了チケットへの返信。例えば顧客がそのチケットへ返信した場合
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          自動フォローアップ
        </entry>
        <entry>
          チケットに対するフォローアップの受付
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          自動拒否
        </entry>
        <entry>
          システムによって行われたチケットの自動拒否
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          自動削除
        </entry>
        <entry>
          システムによって行われたチケットの削除
        </entry>
      </row>
    </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</table>

<note>
<para>
他のOTRSの実体と同様に、自動応答も単に非活性化されるだけであり、削除はできません。（有効オプションを<emphasis>無効</emphasis>または<emphasis>無効-暫定</emphasis>に設定することによって）
</para>
</note>

<para>
To add an auto response to a queue, use the "Auto Response &lt;-&gt; Queues"
link on the Admin page (see figure below). All system events are listed for
every queue, and an auto answer with the same event can be selected or
removed via a listbox.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Queue &lt;-&gt; auto response relations management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-autoresponse-queue.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
To define the different auto responses that will be available for a queue,
click on the corresponding queue name (see figure below). It is also
possible to edit an existing auto response - to do so, click on the response
and edit in the same manner as editing a new auto response.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Change auto response relations for a queue</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/autoresponses-queues-relations.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

</section>
