<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-genericagent">
<title>Executing Automated Jobs with the GenericAgent</title>

<para>
The GenericAgent is a tool to execute tasks automatically. The GenericAgent, for example, can close or move tickets, send notifications on escalated tickets, etc.
</para>

<para>
Click the link "GenericAgent" on the Admin page (see figure below). A table with all automated jobs in the system is displayed. These jobs can then be edited, run manually or removed entirely.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Job list for the GenericAgent</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-genericagent.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
    Click the "Add job" button to create a new job. You first need to supply a name.
    Then you can specify how the job will be executed: automatic at fixed times (like a cronjob, this mode will operate on all tickets found by the ticket filter) or based on ticket events (right after a single ticket was modified, if it matches the ticket filter). Note that if you manually run event based jobs from the overview screen, they will operate on all tickets fund by the ticket filter.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Creating a job for the GenericAgent</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-genericagent-job.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
    For every job, you can specify a ticket filter, for example to only operate on tickets in a certain queue. All filter criteria must be met for a job to be run on a ticket.
</para>
<para>
    Finally, the ticket can be modified by setting various ticket fields like a new queue or state. It is possible to attach a note to the ticket(s) or run a customized module. You also have the option to delete the ticket(s) from the database. This can be useful to purge outdated or invalid data from the system.
    <warning>
        <para>If you use the ticket delete function, all affected tickets and their attachments will be removed from the database and cannot be restored!
        </para>
    </warning>
</para>
<para>
    After editing a job, OTRS will return to the overview screen. There you have the possibility to run any job manually. If you choose to run a job, you will first see all tickets which will be affected when the job actually is run. This list helps you to verify that the job is working as intended. At this point no changes have been made to these tickets yet. Only if you confirm the screen the job will be executed.
</para>
</section>
