<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-package-manager">
<title>Package Manager</title>

<para>
Using the "Package Manager" link on the Admin page, you can install and manage packages that extend the functionality of OTRS (see figure below). See the <link linkend="application">Additional applications</link> section for a discussion on the extensions that are available from the OTRS repositories.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Package Manager</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-packagemanager.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
The Package Manager shows the OTRS addon packages you currently have installed on your server, together with their version numbers.
</para>

<para>You can install packages from a remote host by selecting the repository in the <emphasis>Online Repository</emphasis> section, and clicking the <emphasis>Update repository information</emphasis> button. The available packages are displayed in the corresponding table. The right side of the screen shows the available packages. To install a package, click on <emphasis>Install</emphasis>. After installation, the package is displayed in the <emphasis>Local Repository</emphasis> section.
</para>

<para>
To upgrade an installed package, the list of available packages in the online repository will show <emphasis>Upgrade</emphasis> in the Action column for any package that has a higher version than the one that is installed locally. Just click Upgrade and it will install the new package version on your system.
</para>

<para>
In some cases, such as when your OTRS system is not connected to the Internet, you can also install those packages that you have downloaded to a local disk. Click the <emphasis>Browse</emphasis> button on the Actions side bar, and select the .opm file of the package on your disk. Click <emphasis>Open</emphasis> and then <emphasis>Install Package</emphasis>. After the installation has been completed, the package is displayed in the <emphasis>Local Repository</emphasis> section. You can use the same steps for updating a package that is already installed.
</para>

<para>
In special cases, you might want to configure the Package Manager, e.g., to use a proxy or to use a local repository. Just take a look at the available options in SysConfig under <link linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Core::Package">Framework:Core::Package</link>.
</para>

</section>
