<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-salutations-signatures-attachments-and-answers">
<title>Salutations, Signatures, Attachments and Templates</title>

<section id="adminarea-salutations">
<title>Salutations</title>

<para>
A salutation is a text module for a template. Salutations can be linked to one or more queues, as described in the section about <link linkend="adminarea-queue">queues</link>. A salutation is used only if a ticket from a queue the salutation is linked to, is answered. To manage the different salutations of your system, use the "Salutations"
link of the admin area (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Salutation management</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-salutation.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
After a default installation there is already one salutation available, "system standard salutation (en)".
</para>

<para>
To create a new salutation, press the button "Add salutation", provide the required data and submit it (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Adding a new salutation</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-salutation.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
It is possible to use variables in salutations. When you respond to a ticket, the variable names will be replaced by their values.
</para>

<para>
The different variables you can use in templates are listed in the lower part of the salutation screen. If you use, for example, the variable &lt;OTRS_LAST_NAME&gt; the last name of the ticket's sender  will be included in your reply.
</para>

<note>
<para>
As with other OTRS entities, salutations cannot be deleted, only deactivated by setting the Valid option to <emphasis>invalid</emphasis> or <emphasis>invalid-temporarily</emphasis>.
</para>
</note>

</section>

<section id="adminarea-signatures">
<title>Signatures</title>

<para>
Another text module for a template is the signature. Signatures can be linked to a queue, as described in the section about the <link linkend="adminarea-queue">queues</link>. Please note that a signature will only be appended to a template text, if it has previously been linked to a queue. You can manage the signatures in your system by accessing the "Signatures" link of the Admin page, (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Signatures management</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-signatures.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
After a fresh installation of OTRS, there is one predefined signature stored in your system, "system standard signature (en)".
</para>

<para>
To create a new signature, press the button "Add signature", provide the needed data and submit it (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Adding a new signature</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-signature.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
Like salutations, signatures can also contain dynamic content, such as the first and last name of the agent who answers the ticket. Here too, variables can be used to replace the content of the signature text for every ticket. See the lower part of the signatures screen for the variables which can be used. If you include the variable &lt;OTRS_LAST_NAME&gt; in a signature for example, the last name of the agent who answers the ticket will replace the variable.
</para>

<note>
<para>
As with salutations, signatures too cannot be deleted, only deactivated by setting the Valid option to <emphasis>invalid</emphasis> or <emphasis>invalid-temporarily</emphasis>.
</para>
</note>

</section>

<section id="adminarea-attachments">
<title>Attachments</title>

<para>
You can also optionally add one or more attachments to a template. If the template is selected, the attachments will be attached to the message composition window. If necessary, the agent can remove the attachment from an individual template before sending it to the customer.
</para>

<para>
Through the "Attachment" link of the Admin page, you can load the attachments into the database of the system (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Attachments management</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-attachment.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
To create a new attachment, press the button "Add attachment", provide the required data and submit it (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Adding a new attachment</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-attachment.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
If an attachment is stored it can be linked to one or more templates. Click on the "Attachment &lt;-&gt; Templates"
link of the Admin page (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Linking Attachments to Templates</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-attachment-template.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
To associate different attachments with a specific template and vice versa, click on the corresponding template name or attachment (see below the Figures 4.29 and 4.30, respectively).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Change Attachment relations for a Template</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/template-attachment-relations.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Change Template relations for an Attachment</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/template-attachment-relations2.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

</section>

<section id="adminarea-Templates">
<title>Templates</title>

<para>
    To speed up ticket processing and to standardize the look of answers, you can define templates
    in OTRS. A template can be linked to one or more queues and vice versa.
</para>

<para>
    There are different kind of templates that are used in different parts of OTRS and they have
    its own purpose, the following is the list of possible template types:
</para>
<itemizedlist mark="round">
    <listitem>
        <para>Answer: To be used as a ticket response or reply</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Create: To be used in New Phone or Email ticket</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Forward: To be used to forward an article to someone else</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>PhoneCall: To be used in the Phone Call Inbound and Outbound screens</para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<para>
    Answer templates can be accessed in two ways, from the ticket zoom screen in the article menu,
    or on a quicker way: from any ticket overview large screen such as Status View or Ticket View.
    For a fresh OTRS installation, the "empty answer" template (Answer) is set as the default for
    every queue.
</para>

<para>
    As soon as Forward templates are added and assigned to queues, the "Forward" button in ticket
    zoom (that normally leads to a empty text forward screen) will change into a selection control,
    the selection is filled with the added Forward templates, by choosing one of the templates, the
    forward screen will be shown prefilled with the template text and attachments (similar to the
    reply selection box with the Answer templates).
</para>

<para>
    Creating templates of type Create and PhoneCall will make visible the "Text Template" selection
    box in their respective screens, choosing a template for the list will populate the "Text" and
    "Attachment" fields (if available in the template). Notice that any previous change in the Text
    or attachments will be overwritten by selecting a template.
</para>

<para>
    Clicking the "Templates" link on the Admin page brings you to the Template management screen
    (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Template management</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-template.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
    To create a new template, click on the "Add template" button, provide the required data (make
    sure to select the appropriate template type) and submit it (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Adding a template</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-template.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
To add/remove templates to one or more queues, click on the "Templates &lt;-&gt; Queues" link on the Admin page (see figure below). You can also use filters to get information regarding a specific entity.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Template-Queue relations management</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-template-queue.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
To define the different templates that will be available for a queue and vice versa, click on the corresponding template or queue (see below the Figures 5.32 and 5.33, respectively).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Change Queue relations for a Template</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/template-queue-relations.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Change Template relations for a Queue</title>
    <screenshot>
         <graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/template-queue-relations2.png" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic>
    </screenshot>
</figure>
</para>

<para>
    When choosing a template, additional information could be added to the template text, this
    depends on the template type:
</para>
<para>
    PhoneCall and Create templates does not add any content to the template text, however New Email
    Ticket screen adds the queue assigned signature to the resulting email body (this screen has a
    separated box to visualize the signature).
</para>
<para>
    Answer templates text when selected also included  the salutation associated with the
    queue, then the text of the template, then the quoted ticket text, and finally the signature
    associated with the queue.
</para>
<para>
    Forward templates are similar to Answer templates, but they does not include the salutation
    part.
</para>

</section>

</section>
