<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-auto-responses">
<title>Automatische Antworten</title>

<para>
OTRS allows you to send automatic responses to customers based on the
occurrence of certain events, such as the creation of a ticket in a specific
queue, the receipt of a follow-up message in regards to a ticket, the
closure or rejection of a ticket, etc. To manage such responses, click the
link "Auto responses" on the Admin page (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Auto response management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-autoresponse.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
To create an automatic response, click on the button "Add auto response",
provide the needed data and submit it (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Adding an auto response</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-autoresponse.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
Für die Betreffzeile und den Text von automatischen Antworten kann genauso
wie bei Signaturen oder Anreden, der Inhalt mit Hilfe von OTRS-Variablen
dynamisch erzeugt werden. So werden über die Variable
&lt;OTRS_CUSTOMER_EMAIL[5]&gt; die ersten 5 Zeilen der an das System
gesendeten E-Mail in die automatische Antwort eingefügt, oder durch
&lt;OTRS_CUSTOMER_FROM&gt; die From-Zeile. Die Anmerkungen im unterem
Bereich der Bildschirmmaske zur Verwaltung der automatischen Antworten
listen alle OTRS-Variablen auf, die verwendet werden können.
</para>

<para>
For every automatic answer, you can specify the event that should trigger
it. The system events that are available after a default installation are
described in the Table 4-4.
</para>

<table id="table-of-autoanswer-types">
<title>Events for auto responses</title>
  <tgroup cols="2">
    <thead>
      <row>
        <entry>
          Name
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Beschreibung
        </entry>
      </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <row>
        <entry>
          auto reply
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Dieses Ereignis tritt ein, wenn ein neues Ticket in einer Queue angelegt
wird.
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          auto reply/new ticket
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Dieses Ereignis tritt ein, wenn ein bereits geschlossenes Ticket,
z. B. durch die Antwort eines Kunden, mit einer neuen Ticketnummer erneut
geöffnet wird.
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          auto follow up
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Dieses Ereignis tritt ein, wenn ein Follow up für ein bereits vorhandenes
Ticket eintrifft.
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          auto reject
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Dieses Ereignis tritt ein, wenn ein Ticket vom System zurückgewiesen wird.
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          auto remove
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Dieses Ereignis tritt ein, wenn ein Ticket vom System entfernt wird.
        </entry>
      </row>
    </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</table>

<note>
<para>
As with other OTRS entities, auto responses too cannot be deleted, only
deactivated, by setting the Valid option to <emphasis>invalid</emphasis> or
<emphasis>invalid-temporarily</emphasis>.
</para>
</note>

<para>
To add an auto response to a queue, use the "Auto Response &lt;-&gt; Queues"
link on the Admin page (see figure below). All system events are listed for
every queue, and an auto answer with the same event can be selected or
removed via a listbox.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Queue &lt;-&gt; auto response relations management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-autoresponse-queue.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
To define the different auto responses that will be available for a queue,
click on the corresponding queue name (see figure below). It is also
possible to edit an existing auto response - to do so, click on the response
and edit in the same manner as editing a new auto response.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Change auto response relations for a queue</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/autoresponses-queues-relations.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

</section>
