<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="customers-and-groups">
<title>Kundenbenutzer und Kundengruppen</title>

<section id="adminarea-customers">
<title>Kunden</title>

<para>
OTRS supports different types of users. Using the link "Customers" (via the
navigation bar, or the Admin page), you can manage the accounts of your
customers (see figure below), who can log into the system via the Customers
interface (customer.pl). Through this interface, your customers can not only
create tickets but also review their past tickets for new updates. It is
important to know that a customer is needed for the ticket history in the
system.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Kundenverwaltung</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-customer.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
Neben der Möglichkeit in der Datenbank nach einem bestimmten Kunden zu
suchen, kann das Backend umgestellt werden, über das auf die Kundendaten
zugegriffen wird. In OTRS lassen sich mehrere Datenbanken mit Kundendaten
einbinden, genauere Informationen hierzu finden Sie im Abschnitt <link
linkend="external-backends">Einbinden externer Backends für Agents und
Customer</link>.
</para>

<para>
To create a new customer account, click on the "Add customer" button (see
figure below). Some of the fields are mandatory, i.e., they have to contain
values, so if you leave one of those empty, it will be highlighted in red.
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Adding a customer</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/add-customer.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
Der Kunde kann mit Benutzername und Passwort auf das System zugreifen. Die
Kundennummer wird vom System benötigt, um den Kunden und seine Tickets zu
erkennen. Da E-Mail-Adressen eindeutig sind, können sie als ID verwendet
werden.
</para>

<note>
<para>
In OTRS können Kunden deaktivert, aber nicht gelöscht werden. Sie können
einen Kunden deaktivieren, indem Sie den Wert für "Gültig" auf "ungültig"
oder "ungültig-temporär" setzen.
</para>
</note>

</section>

<section id="adminarea-customers-groups">
<title>Kundengruppen</title>

<para>
Kunden können auch Gruppen zugeordnet werden. Das ist nützlich, wenn Kunden
nur auf bestimmte Queues zugreifen können sollen. Legen Sie zuerst die
benötigten Gruppen in der <link linkend="adminarea-groups">
Gruppenverwaltung </link> an . Fügen Sie dann die <link
linkend="adminarea-queue"> Queues </link> hinzu und ordnen Sie diese der
neuen Gruppe zu.
</para>

<para>
The next step is to activate the customer group support. This can be done
with the configuration parameter <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Frontend::Customer:CustomerGroupSupport">CustomerGroupSupport</link>,
from the Admin SysConfig option. Using the parameter <link
linkend="ConfigReference_Framework:Frontend::Customer:CustomerGroupAlwaysGroups">CustomerGroupAlwaysGroups</link>,
you can specify the default groups for a newly added customer, so that every
new account will be automatically added to these groups.
</para>

<para>
Through the link "Customers &lt;-&gt; Groups" you can manage which customer
shall belong to the different groups (see figure below).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Customer-Group relations management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-customer-groups.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
To define the different groups a customer should be part of and vice versa,
click on the corresponding customer username or group (see below the Figures
4.18 and 4.19, respectively).
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Gruppenzuordnungen eines Kunden bearbeiten</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/groups-customers-relations.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

<para>
<figure>
    <title>Kundenzuordnungen einer Gruppe bearbeiten</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/groups-customers-relations2.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
</para>

</section>

</section>
