<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="daemon">
    <title>The OTRS Daemon</title>
    <para>
        The OTRS Daemon is an independent set of system processes that plan and
execute tasks in background, either on a recurrent basis or triggered by
events. OTRS Daemon is fundamental for the correct system operation.
    </para>
    <para>
        In previous versions of OTRS (from 3.1 to 4) there was another process
called OTRS Scheduler that does part of the work that the OTRS Demon do in
OTRS 5. This old process is replaced by the OTRS Daemon which was re-written
from the ground to make it more stable, scalable and robust than its
predecessor.
    </para>
    <para>
        The OTRS Daemon is capable to handle up to 10 tasks at the same time and it
can work cooperatively with other OTRS Daemons on different frontend servers
in a cluster environment.
    </para>
    <para>
        When idle OTRS Daemon consist in five processes:
        <itemizedlist mark="round">
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    The main daemon (<filename>bin/otrs.Daemon.pl</filename>)
                </para>
                <para>
                    This process is in charge to start and keep running the other children
daemons.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Task worker daemon
(<filename>Kernel/System/Daemon/DaemonModules/SchedulerTaskWorker.pm</filename>)
                </para>
                <para>
                    This daemon executes all tasks that have in a list, in a first in first out
basis, it can handle handle simultaneous tasks by creating its own children
processes and it check the task list several times per second. The task list
can be filled by task manager daemons, event handlers, and other parts of
the system.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Its main mission is to handle all the tasks in the list as soon as possible.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Future task manager daemon
(<filename>Kernel/System/Daemon/DaemonModules/SchedulerFutureTaskManager.pm</filename>)
                </para>
                <para>
                    This daemon checks for non recurring tasks that are set to be executed in
the future ( e.g. when a Generic Interface invoker tries to reach a server
and it can't, a task could be set to schedule for execution in the next 5
minutes). When is the correct time it sends it the task worker daemon.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Cron task manager daemon
(<filename>Kernel/System/Daemon/DaemonModules/SchedulerCronTaskManager.pm</filename>)
                </para>
                <para>
                    This daemon calculates when is the next execution time of all recurring
tasks ( e.g. a cache cleanup one time per week ). This kind of tasks are
specified in the SysConfig, at the right time for each task it sends the
required information to the task worker daemon to execute them.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Generic Agent task manager daemon
(<filename>Kernel/System/Daemon/DaemonModules/SchedulerGenericAgentTaskManager.pm</filename>)
                </para>
                <para>
                    This daemon scans for Generic Agent jobs stored in the database that have a
time schedule (discarding all other Generic Agent jobs that are set to
executed by events). When is time to run a Generic Agent job it sends the
task information to the task worker daemon to handle the task.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <note>
        <para>
            The number of active processes depends on the number of tasks that the OTRS
Daemon is executing simultaneously in a time frame.
        </para>
    </note>
    <para>
        By default the each daemon logs all error messages on a separated file
located in: <filename>/opt/otrs/var/log/Daemon/*.log</filename> this logs
are kept in the system for a defined period, to change this behavior and/or
to also log the non error messages please update SysConfig settings in
<literal>Daemon</literal> -> <literal>Core::Log</literal>
    </para>
    <para>
        When a task could not be executed successfully for any reason, an email is
sent to a predefined recipient reporting the issue, the content of the email
includes the error messages and trace (if available).
    </para>
    <para>
        The OTRS Daemon is an automated process that normally does not require human
interaction, however it is possible to query its status and start or stop it
if needed.
    </para>
    <para>
        To be sure that the OTRS Daemon is running there is a Cron job that
constantly checks that the process is alive. The main daemon is prepared to
work even without a database connection, so is perfectly safe if the Cron
task to start it is executed even before the database process in the system
startup, and it is also tolerant to database disconnections.
    </para>
    <para>
        If for any reason the OTRS Daemon needs to be stop, for example during a
system maintenance all unhandled tasks are saved, and as soon as the process
is started again it continues with all pending tasks, for recurring tasks it
will only execute the last instance of the task ( if is due time was during
the downtime ).
    </para>
    <section id="daemon-gui">
        <title>OTRS Daemon Graphical Interface</title>
        <para>
            The OTRS Daemon is not visible in the OTRS Graphical User Interface unless
it stops running.
        </para>
        <para>
            When the system detects that the OTRS Daemon is not running, a notification
is presented to a defined group of users ("admin" by default)
        </para>
        <para>
            To disable the notification (not recommended), change or add the
notification groups, please edit the
"Frontend::NotifyModule###800-Daemon-Check" setting in the SysConfig.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Daemon notification</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/daemon-notify.png"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
        <para>
            Clicking the notification the system presents an overlay window explaining
the steps to bring the OTRS Daemon up and running.
        </para>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Start Daemon</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/daemon-start.png"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section id="daemon-cli">
        <title>OTRS Daemon Command Line Interface</title>
        <para>
            The OTRS Daemon command line tools let you control the main daemon process
(Start / Stop)  or query its status. There are also tools to get more
detailed information about the other four children daemons.
        </para>
        <section id="daemon-cli-main">
            <title>Main Daemon Tools</title>
            <para>
                To start, stop or query daemon status
<filename>bin/otrs.Daemon.pl</filename> script is used.
            </para>
            <example>
                <title>Example to start the OTRS Daemon</title>
                <para>
                    <screen><![CDATA[
shell> cd /opt/otrs/
shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Daemon.pl start
                    ]]></screen>
                </para>
            </example>
            <itemizedlist mark="round">
                <title>Verfügbare Optionen</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>start</command> - to start the OTRS Daemon process.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>stop</command> - to stop the OTRS Daemon process.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>status</command> - to query the OTRS Damon process status.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                   <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>start --debug</command> - to start the OTRS Daemon process in debug
mode.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            In this mode the each daemon reports different messages depending on the
actions that are been executed. This mode is not recommended for production
environments.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                   <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>stop --force</command> - to stop the OTRS Daemon process in
reducing the wait for children processes to finish.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            A forced stop reduces the amount of time the main daemon waits to successful
stop the other children processes from 30 seconds (normal)  to 5 seconds
(forced).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
             </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section id="daemon-cli-other">
            <title>Other Daemon Tools</title>
            <para>
                To list all configured child daemons that the main daemon should start and
keep running use the console command:
<literal>Maint::Daemon::List</literal>.
            </para>
            <example>
                <title>Example to list all configured daemons</title>
                <para>
                    <screen><![CDATA[
shell> cd /opt/otrs/
shell> bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::Daemon::List
                    ]]></screen>
                </para>
            </example>
            <para>
                To list detailed information of all daemons use the console command:
<literal>Maint::Daemon::Summary</literal>.
            </para>
            <example>
                <title>Example to a summary of all daemon tasks</title>
                <para>
                    <screen><![CDATA[
shell> cd /opt/otrs/
shell> bin/otrs.Console.pl Maint::Daemon::Summary
                    ]]></screen>
                </para>
            </example>
        </section>
    </section>
</section>
