<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="adminarea-ticket-notifications">
    <title>Уведомления по заявкам</title>

    <para>
        OTRS allows ticket notifications to be sent to agents and customers, based
on the occurrence of certain events.  Agents can customize their ticket
notification settings via the <link
linkend="user-preferences">preferences</link> link.
    </para>

    <para>
        Through the "Ticket Notifications" link on the Admin page, you can manage
the ticket notifications of your system (see figure below).  OTRS comes with
a set of predefined notifications that cover a wide range of use cases.
<figure>
            <title>Ticket notification management</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-notification-overview.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
    </para>

    <para>
        You can customize many aspects of the notifications.  Click on the
notification you want to change, and its content will be loaded for editing
(see figure below).  <figure>
            <title>Customizing a notification</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-notification-basic.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure> You can edit the
basic data of this notification such as name and comment, and control if the
agents may choose to receive this notification (per transport method). For
every language, a subject and body can be added/edited to configure what
will actually be sent as the notification content.  Just as with signatures
and salutations, it is possible to dynamically create the content of a
notification by using special variables. You can find a list of variables at
the bottom of the screen.
    </para>

    <para>
        You can choose which events should trigger this notification, and limit it
to tickets which match certain criteria (ticket and/or article filter). This
makes it possible to create different notifications for different queues,
priorities or other criteria that might be relevant for your system.
    </para>

    <para>
        The recipients of the notification can be configured according to different
criteria (groups, roles, individual agents etc.).  All configured recipients
will receive the notification.  <figure>
            <title>Customizing a notification's recipients</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-notification-recipients.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
Additionally, you can specify if the notification should be sent to agents
who are out of office, and limit the sending to once per day and ticket
(e. g. pending reminder notification).
    </para>

    <para>
        Notifications can be sent with different notification methods. The "Email"
notification method is available in OTRS Free, with <emphasis
role="bold">OTRS Business Solution™</emphasis> you also get the possibility
to store and view the notifications in the database (so that no email client
is needed to use OTRS) as well as to send them via SMS (e. g. for very
important notifications).  <figure>
            <title>Customizing notification methods</title>
<screenshot>
<graphic
fileref="screenshots/administration/adminarea/admin-notification-transports.png"
scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"></graphic></screenshot></figure>
    </para>
</section>
